Guide to the School of Medicine, Yale University, Audio Recordings of Events and Programs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Medicine, Yale University, audio recordings of events and programs
1964-1969
RU 1040
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1
(15 audiotapes)
The materials consist of audio recordings of symposia, programs, and other events held at the School of Medicine.
Yale University. School of Medicine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-H (YRG 27-H), Audio-visual materials and memorabilia documenting the Yale School of Medicine.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were a gift of Arthur Ebbert, 1982.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of audio recordings of symposia, programs, and other events held at the School of Medicine. Included are recordings of meetings of the Connecticut State Medical Society and Yale Medical Society, as well as Yale School of Medicine Alumni Day programs and the appointment of Fredrick Redlich as dean of the School of Medicine.
Arrangement
The records are arranged chronologically.
Congresses and conventions; Audiotapes; Connecticut State Medical Society; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Alumni; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Audiorecordings, 1964-1969; Accession 1982-A-065; 1
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - YALE MEDICAL SOCIETY -SYMPOSIUM, "Moral Issues in Clinical Research", 1964 January 14; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Dr. Paul Beeson; Dr. Philip Boucher; Prof. John Smith; Prof. Richard Donnelly (approx 80 minutes)
  - CONNECTICUT STATE MEDICAL SOCIETY, 1965 September 24
    - Part 1, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
      Welcome and opening remarks; Dr. James R. Cullen, Bacterial Infections; Dr. Abraham I. Brande, Viral Infections Dr. Edwin D. Kilbourne
    - Part 2, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
      Panel Discussion: Drs. Atkins, Brande Andriole, D. Horstman; Clinical Pathological Conference: Drs. J.C. Leonard, Kuscher, Melnick; Discussant Dr. Jacob Fine
    - Part 3, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 5)
      Cardio genic Shock/M.H. Luria; Shock due to Infection, Dr. J. Fine; Hemorrhagic and Traumatic Shock, R. Lillehei
    - Part 4, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 4)
      Panel Discussion: Drs. W.W. Glenn, M.H. Luria, J.Fine, R. C. Lillehei
  - REDLICH APPOINTMENT SPEECH, 1967 March 14; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 6)
    INFORMAL COMMENTS BY DR. REDLICH AT SPECIAL MEETING OF FACULTY AT WHICH KINGMAN BREWSTER ANNOUNCED HIS APPOINTMENT AS DEAN.
  - YALE SCHOOL OF MEDICINE, ALUMNI DAY PROGRAM, 1968 June 8; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel)
    - Part 1, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 7)
      Dr. Benjamin Castleman, Dr. F.C. Redlich, Dr. Leona Baumgartner; Dr. Paul Talalay, "Drugs in Our Society"
    - Part 2, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 8)
      Dr. Donald W. Seldin, "Social and Academic Responsibilities of Medical Schools;" Dr. Louis G. Welt, "Medical Education" Preparation for Tomorrow"
  - Faculty meeting, 1969 June 5; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
  - Alumni Day program, 1969; 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 10)
  - Medical School Symposium, undated
    - Part 1, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 11)
    - Part 2, 1 audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 12)